=Godslayer=
(Adapted from the novel Godslayer.)
A clash of blades
is merely a contest between mortals.
The heavens created mankind,
shaping them from clay.
To achieve immortality,
one must shed the mortal form
and become refined porcelain.
Master Lu?
What did you do to her?
Lu Yuanqing.
Hand over the ice silkworm.
She
can only be mine.
=Episode 10=
(She Can Only Be Mine)
He refined a twin manifestation,
turning the silkworm monster Lu Ji
into part of himself.
He's insane.
Mere mortals
could never harm me.
His porcelain armor cannot be broken
from the outside.
Then what do we do?
(It's Master Lu's ice silkworm.)
This is a fragment of my
spiritual consciousness
left inside the ice silkworm.
I know
you are bound to reach
this point someday.
To face him.
Just like you,
he emerged from the Ice Lake
and fought his way to the Upper City.
(Ten Years Ago)
The Medicine Lodge
is giving out porridge
to aid those suffering on the journey.
All travelers are welcome.
Line up and take your share.
Thank you.
Move!
You're this skinny
and still haven't starved?
The Essence-Nourishing Porridge is
for those entering the Ascension Trial.
It's wasted on you.
You want to pick up the bowl too?
Go on, pick it up!
The Medicine Lodge gives porridge
without asking where people come from.
Without lining up,
you get nothing.
Go. Go.
Mr. Bai.
Your disciple has reached
the right age, hasn't she?
All the young men in my place
are preparing for the Ascension Trial.
Let her take a look.
She can take a look at our boys.
See if any catches her eye.
I'm worried about that too.
Ask her yourself.
She...
Whoever can retrieve the Reverse Scale
from the Ice Lake,
I'll marry him.
Ice Lake?
Our bones would melt away
the moment we enter.
Master Lu,
this isn't a marriage proposal.
You're asking people to die.
Then it means you aren't capable
of marrying me.
Who is there?
The Ice Lake...
I went there.
And Cang and Yi...
I defeated them too.
But the Reverse Scale was frozen.
I couldn't take it out.
Master!
Here, drink this medicine.
You're really foolish.
Once my wounds heal,
I'll go again.
Go where?
To the Ice Lake.
I'll definitely bring it back.
I was just saying that.
I'm serious.
Your heart meridian is injured.
If my master hadn't used
the fire silkworm to mend it,
you would already be dead.
I know.
Next time,
I'll be stronger.
Lie down.
You are not allowed to go to
the Ice Lake again.
Do you really have to leave?
Once I make a name for myself,
I'll bring you to the Capital.
To the Upper City
to see the lanterns.
But half-monsters are forbidden
from entering the Upper City.
If I win,
I'll change this stupid rule.
I'll let all half-monsters
enter the capital freely.
They can go wherever they want
and never have to bow to anyone again.
This is the ice silkworm inside me.
The fire silkworm mended
into your heart meridian is its twin.
My master said twin silkworms
can connect our hearts
and share our spiritual consciousness.
So,
our hearts are bound together.
Right?
Wait for me.
I will come back for you.
Then
did he come back?
He...
He came back.
But the person he once was
is dead.
(I promised you)
(I would take you to the Capital.)
(Ride my carriage into the city.)
(No one will dare stop you,)
(nor question you.)
(Okay. I'll go to the Capital with you,)
(what about them?)
(What?)
(What are those Porcelain
Armored Soldiers outside for?)
(They...)
(Don't lie to me.)
(Has the rule forbidding half-monsters
from entering the Upper City)
(changed?)
(I just became Lord
of the Heavenly Law.)
(In the Capital, I walk on thin ice.)
(I cannot let them know who you are.)
(The half-monsters, exiled criminals
and escaped slaves)
(in the Medicine Lodge)
(must all be dealt with.)
(You are no longer foolish.)
(I did all this for you.)
(You still don't understand.)
(I told you.)
(The man I marry)
(must be the one who can retrieve
the Reverse Scale.)
(Master.)
(He lost his way in the Capital.)
He never found his way back.
To reach the Divine Sovereign Realm
through the power of heavenly thunder,
step by step,
he killed the person he used to be.
But he has not fully achieved it yet.
You still have a chance to stop him.
How can I break through his armor?
The ice silkworm within you
and the fire silkworm within him
share a Twin Bond.
They can connect
your spiritual consciousness.
Enter the realm
of his spiritual consciousness
and find his cultivating
primordial spirit.
Destroy that primordial spirit,
and his shield armor
will collapse on its own.
I can send you inside.
I'll enter his consciousness
and take a look.
(Who is the Challenger?)
(Dazedi.)
(Wang Yan.)
(Life and death shall be disregarded!)
(Begin the battle!)
(The Challenger wins.)
(Dare you enter and face
your truest desire?)
(By divine decree,)
(you are hereby appointed Lord
of the Heavenly Law,)
(overseeing the affairs
of the Heavenly Law Bureau.)
(May you uphold justice, fulfill
your duties, and serve with devotion.)
(My greetings,
Lord of the Heavenly Law.)
(The Medicine Lodge
is full of corruption.)
(It should have been cleansed long ago.)
(You gave him the ice silkworm?)
You said
that our hearts
were bound by a Twin Bond.
Am I right?
This way,
you will never leave me again.
Why
would you do this to Master Lu?
Because of you!
You should never have
gone to the Ice Lake!
You should never have taken
the Reverse Scale!
And she should never have given you
the ice silkworm!
Both the Reverse Scale and her
should belong to me!
You're insane.
You think you're any different from me?
You fought your way here,
killing your way forward.
You stand here
because you were stronger than them.
This world
has always been ruled by the strong
over the weak.
The Reverse Scale chose you.
She chose you too.
It's only because you won.
Now she is with me
because I am stronger than you.
If you think you're capable,
come and take her.
(Back then,)
(his heart meridian
was severely wounded.)
(Though the fire silkworm
repaired the wound,)
(he still carried a hidden weakness
in his chest.)
(That is his only weakness.)
Let me end this.
Heavenly Thunder of the Divine
Sovereign Realm,
All Thunder Returns!
This world has never been about
the strong ruling over the weak.
She left a spiritual consciousness
within the ice silkworm.
Before it faded away,
the last person she wanted to see...
was you.
(The Medicine Lodge
is giving out porridge)
(to aid those suffering on the journey.)
(All travelers are welcome.)
(Line up and take your share.)
(Hey.)
(Your turn.)
(I have been waiting for you all along.)
(I gave you a bowl of porridge,)
(not so that you would give me
the entire Capital.)
(It's a pity you never understood me.)
(It was me...)
(I was the one who was wrong.)
(It's alright.)
(The Capital is too vast.)
(You simply lost your way.)
(Whoever can retrieve the Reverse Scale
from the Ice Lake,)
(I will marry him.)
(You are not allowed to go to
the Ice Lake again.)
(I was just saying that.)
(Do you really have to leave?)
(Hey.)
(You're really foolish.)
This is...
"A silkworm's thread ends
only when it dies."
The silkworm monster's life has ended,
but if regrets remain in its heart,
and unfinished threads remain,
it will form a cocoon,
waiting to break free again,
to become human,
and gain consciousness.
But no one knows how long it will take.
It may be ten years.
Or it may be a lifetime.
She waited for me her entire life.
I will wait for her too.
(Come home, lost child.)
(The path to Yuyou Village)
(has only ever been opened by the Lord
of the Heavenly Law throughout history.)
Thank you.
No need.
This is a path you carved yourself.
What will you do now?
I will leave the heavens
and walk back down to the mortal world.
Your little sister knows you're here.
She is waiting for you.
Mortal sinner.
How dare you trespass into
the forbidden grounds of Yuyou Village.
I have led the Heavenwrights here
to uphold the heavenly order.
If you wish to go up,
you must first get past us.
That's right. Get past us first!
Exactly!
Well said!